SRITHARAN BRAVEENAN

+94 77 226 7008 \diamond 32, 8/5, Madhangahawattalane ,Colombo-06, Sri Lanka Mail \diamond LinkedIn \diamond Website \diamond GitHub

OBJECTIVE

Enthusiastic and energetic individual with problem-solving and critical-thinking skills, committed team member with excellent communication skills, and leadership qualities. Conducted academic research in the fields of Signal Processing, Autonomous Systems, and Machine Learning. Gained professional experience in Digital System Design, Machine Learning, and Software Development.

WORK HISTORY

Teaching Assistant (part time) University of Moratuwa	September 2022 - Now
Research Assistant University of Moratuwa	May 2022 - Now
Software Engineer Axiata Digital Labs (Pvt) Ltd	July 2021 - May 2022
Software Engineer Intern Paraqum Technologies (Pvt) Ltd	August 2019 - December 2019
Software Engineer Intern Wave Computing (Pvt) Ltd	June 2019 - August 2019

EDUCATION

M.Sc.(Major component Research), University of Moratuwa

August 2022 - Now

Specialized in Computer Science and Engineering

B.Sc.(Hons)Engineering, University of Moratuwa

October 2016 - July 2021

Specialized in Electronic and Telecommunication Engineering

Second Class Upper Division

GPA: 3.56

Dean's List in Semester 1, Semester 7 and Semester 8

HONORS & AWARDS

\bullet Mahapola Higher Education Merit Scholarship granted by the Government of Sri Lanka	2016 - 2021
• Silver Medalist in Sri Lankan Physics Olympiad	2015
• Credit pass in Australian National Chemistry Quiz Senior Division	2014
• Merit pass in Australian National Chemistry Quiz Junior Division	2012
• Merit pass (Ranked 16) in Sri Lankan Mathematics Junior Challenge Competition	2011

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages	Python, MATLAB, C++, Java, SQL, Verilog
Tools	Git, Linux

PROJECTS

Project 1 Real-Time Light Field Video Compression using 5-D Approximate Discrete Cosine Transform 2020

Objective is to develop a real-time Light Field Video (LFV) Compression system for efficient transmission and storage purposes.

Objective is to build an inventory management system with an autonomous quad-copter that minimizes cost and makes inventorying task of warehouses more efficient.

Project 3 Unified Voice Model

On going

Objective is to develop a unified model for Speaker, Speech and Emotion Recognition using Multi-task Learning and create a unified embedding which can differentiate and explain speaker, speech and emotion related features.

OTHER PROJECTS

• COVID19 symptoms detector – Community project	2020
• Custom Processor Design and Implementation to Down sample an Image	2019
• IoT oil lamp – Community project	2018
PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	

P

• Resource person - Workshop on Light Field Processing Using Low-Complexity Signal Proce	essing Algorithms and
Deep Learning at IEEE EMBS International Student Conference 2021	2021

• Resource person - Workshop on Sequence-to-Sequence Models in Deep Learning at MERCon 2023

• Web Master - IEEE Communications Society Student Branch Chapter of University of Moratuwa 2020 - 2021

• Student Coordinator - Tamil Literary Association, University Of Moratuwa 2020 - 2021

• Editor - IEEE Communications Society Student Branch Chapter of University of Moratuwa 2019 - 2020

• Team leader - Archiventure 1.0, AIESEC Colombo South

2018

2023

• Resource person - Robotic workshop for school children organized by Electronic Club of UOM

2018

• Student Representative - Dept. of Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering, UOM

2017 - 2018

REFERENCES

Dr. Uthavasanker Thavasivam

Senior Lecturer,

Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering,

University of Moratuwa,

Sri Lanka

Email: rtuthaya@cse.mrt.ac.lk

Dr. Chamira U. S. Edussooriya

Senior Lecturer,

Dept. of Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering,

University of Moratuwa,

Sri Lanka

Email: chamira@uom.lk

Prof. Rohan Munasinghe

Professor.

Dept. of Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering,

University of Moratuwa,

Sri Lanka

Email: rohan@uom.lk